Guide to the Bernard Greenberg Collection, 1951-1988 AIS.2010.09
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Bernard Greenberg Collection
1951-1988
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Greenberg, Bernard (Economist)
AIS.2010.09
10 Linear Feet (8 boxes)
Bernard Greenberg worked for the United Steelworkers of America's Department of Pensions and Insurance. This collection contains reports regarding health care and insurance, as well as applications of companies to be approved as health service agencies in Pennsylvania.
Previous Citation
Bernard Greenberg Collection, 1951-1988, AIS.2010.09, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Biography
Bernard Greenberg was an economist for the United Steelworkers of America's Department of Pensions and Insurance. He began working for the union in 1949 and also served as the assistant director of benefits and pensions. Greenberg was a member of the Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania Review Committee during the 1980s.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains reports regarding health care and insurance. Also included are applications of companies to be approved as health service agencies according to Pennsylvania law. Studies on Soviet and American health care providers are also present, as well as conference proceedings.
Labor; Regional medical programs -- Pennsylvania, Southwestern; Labor unions and public health -- United States; Health and medicine; Business and Industry; United Steelworkers of America. Department of Pensions and Insurance; Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania; Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania. Review Committee
- Health Resources Statistics Reported from the National Center for Health Statistics, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Item 1-2)
- Vital and Health Statistics: Data from the National Health Survey, Nursing Homes in the United States, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Item 3)
- Health, United States, 1981 (Box 1, Item 4)
- Health Manpower: A County and Metropolitan Area Data Book, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Item 5)
- National Health Insurance Proposals: Provisions of Bills Introduced in the 93rd Congress, July 1974 (Box 1, Item 6)
- Compendium of National Health Expenditures Data, 1976 (Box 1, Item 7)
- Reforming the Military Health Care System, Congressional Budget Office Study, 1988 (Box 1, Item 8)
- Health Care for All Americans Act, September 6, 1979 (Box 1, Item 9)
- National Health Systems in Eight Countries by Joseph G. Simanis, 1975 (Box 1, Item 10)
- Forward Plan for Health, US Department of Health, Education and Welfare, FY 1977-81 and FY 1978-82, June 1975, August 1976 (Box 1, Item 11-12)
- The American Journal of Public Health, March 1976, October 1987, January-March 1988 (Box 1, Item 13-17)
- Health PAC Bulletin by the Health Policy Advisory Center, 1981-1988 (Box 1, Item 18-30)
- Health Law Project Library Bulletin, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Item 31-62)
- A Report to the President: Medical Care Prices by the Department of Health, Education and Welfare, February 1967 (Box 1, Item 63)
- The Complex Puzzle of Rising Health Care Costs: Can the Private Sector Fit It Together?, December 1976 (Box 1, Item 64)
- Medicare and Medicaid: Problems, Issues and Alternatives, February 9, 1970 (Box 1, Item 65)
- A Discursive Dictionary of Health Care, February 1976 (Box 1, Item 66)
- Pro-Life Reporter, 1978 (Box 2, Item 1)
- Disability Survey, 1981 (Box 2, Item 2)
- Survey of Disability and Work, Data Book, 1978 (Box 2, Item 3)
- Industrial Relations Research Association, Membership Directory, 1987 (Box 2, Item 4)
- Preventative Medicine: An International Journal Devoted to Practice and Theory, March 1972 (Box 2, Item 5)
- Quality Health Care at the Lowest Cost, March 29, 1979 (Box 2, Item 6)
- The Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, Annual Report, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Item 7-8)
- The Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, Special Report, 1979 (Box 2, Item 9)
- New Horizons in Health Care, Proceedings of the First International Congress on Group Medicine, April 26-30, 1970 (Box 2, Item 10)
- A Handbook for Consumer Participation in Health Care Planning, 1977 (Box 2, Item 11)
- Range Mental Health Center, Experimental Health Care Delivery System Project (Box 2, Item 12)
- Speakers at the Upper Peninsula Health Care Conference, September 12, 1975 (Box 2, Item 13)
- One Day Census: A Study of Patients in Michigan Hospitals, Part I Summary Statistics, November 15, 1962 (Box 2, Item 14)
- Michigan Hospital Service, 23rd Annual Report, 1961 (Box 2, Item 15)
- University of Michigan School of Public Health, Medical Care Chart Book, 1968 (Box 2, Item 16)
- Viewpoint, 1980 (Box 2, Item 17)
- Labor Looks at Congress: An AFL-CIO Legislative Report, 1978 (Box 2, Item 18)
- Soviet Public Health and the Organization of Primary Health Care for the Population of the USSR, 1978 (Box 2, Item 19)
- Comparative Medicine: East and West, 1978 (Box 2, Item 20)
- Proceedings, XXII Annual Group Health Institute, May 16-17, 1972 (Box 2, Item 21)
- The National Economy, 1969 (Box 2, Item 22)
- Health and Society: The Milbank Memorial Fund Quarterly, 1973 (Box 2, Item 23)
- The Nature and Interrelationships of the Private and Public Sectors in Health Services by Dr. Eli Ginzberg, 1983 (Box 2, Item 24)
- Can Health be Planned? by Aaron Wildavsky, 1976 (Box 2, Item 25)
- Penn Group Health Plan for Members of USWA (Box 2, Item 26)
- Labor's Role in a Free Society by George Meany (Box 2, Item 27)
- Five Seminars on Emerging Sectors of Collective Bargaining, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Item 28)
- National Academy of Arbitrators, Membership Directory, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Item 29)
- Debs' Legacy and Labor's Struggle Today, March 13, 1975 (Box 2, Item 30)
- National Industrial Group Pension Plan, May 3, 1974 (Box 2, Item 31)
- How the Union Serves, 1975 (Box 2, Item 32)
- Rights and Responsibilities by the Office of Labor Management Standards Enforcement, September 1977 (Box 2, Item 33)
- Writing the Collective Bargaining Agreement & Costing Out the Collective Bargaining Agreement, 1979 (Box 2, Item 34)
- Improving Employee Relations Through Effective Discipline and Grievance Procedures & The "Investigatory" Grievance, 1979 (Box 2, Item 35)
- United Steelworkers Oldtimers... A Political Force Ready for Action (Box 2, Item 36)
- Often-Asked Questions About the Employee Retirement Income Security Act, 1974 (Box 2, Item 37)
- Industrial Relations Research Association Series: Proceedings of the Thirty-Ninth Annual Meeting, December 28-30, 1986 (Box 2, Item 38)
- Collective Bargaining: Democracy on the Job, 1965 (Box 2, Item 39)
- Explanation of HR 15301 Railroad Retirement Act Amendments, July 1974 (Box 2, Item 40)
- Arbitration between Coordinating Committee Steel Companies and United Steelworkers of America, "Rule of 65" Pension Arbitration Award, 1978 (Box 2, Item 41)
- The Soviet Health Service (Box 2, Item 42)
- The Main Stages, The State and Prospects for Developing Therapeutical and Preventative Aid for the Population of the USSR, 1978 (Box 2, Item 43)
- The Developing Crisis in International Trade, 1970 (Box 2, Item 44)
- Soviet Medical Instrument Guides (Box 2, Item 45)
- The Right to Social Security in Czechoslovakia, 1957 (Box 2, Item 46)
- Mother-And-Child: Welfare in the Rumanian People's Republic, 1957 (Box 2, Item 47)
- New York University, Twenty-Eighth Annual Conference on Labor, 1976 (Box 2, Item 48)
- Wage Costs and Prices in Basic Steel Products by David Hecker and Mil Lieberthal, 1982 (Box 2, Item 49)
- The Changing Situation of Workers and Their Unions, February 1985 (Box 2, Item 50)
- The Bisbee Deportation by Philip Taft, 1972 (Box 2, Item 51)
- Labor Looks at the Crisis in Civil Rights, 1959 (Box 2, Item 52)
- Public Health and Social Security in the USSR (Box 2, Item 53)
- Pennsylvania Workmen's Compensation & Occupational Disease Provisions, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Item 54)
- Workmen's Compensation Handbook, 1978 (Box 2, Item 55)
- NBER Summary Report: Pensions and the Labor Market by David A. Wise, 1984 (Box 2, Item 56)
- All-Union N.A. Semashko Research Institute of Social Hygiene and Public Health Administration, 1980 (Box 2, Item 57)
- Labor and the European Communities by Meyer Bernstein, 1961 (Box 2, Item 58)
- United States of America Wage Stabilization Board, United Steelworkers of Amerca v. Various Steel and Iron Ore Companies (Box 2, Item 59)
- Appendix, Hearings Before the Subcommittee on Labor of the Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, United States Senate, 1974 (Box 2, Item 60)
- Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, Insurance Department Report, 1956 (Box 2, Item 61)
- Employee Retirement Income Security Act and Pension Reform Act, 1974 (Box 2, Item 62)
- Hospital Services in the USSR, June 26-July 16, 1965 (Box 2, Item 63)
- Political Affairs: Journal of Marxist Thought, August 1978 (Box 2, Item 64)
- The 28th Annual Conference on Labor, 1975 (Box 2, Item 65)
- George Meany Center for Labor Studies, Catalogue, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Item 66)
- AFL-CIO Platform Proposals Presented to the Democratic and Republican National Conventions, 1976 (Box 2, Item 67)
- United States Railway Association, Preliminary System Plan, 1975 (Box 2, Item 68)
- Proceedings, 12th Biennial Conference, USWA District 38, June 16-18, 1976 (Box 2, Item 69)
- Health Resources Planning and Development, Inc. (Box 3, Item 1-2)
- Health Resources Planning and Development, Inc., Application, 1979 (Box 3, Item 3)
- Health Resources Planning and Development, Inc., Appendicies-Health Systems Plan, 1979 (Box 3, Item 4)
- Health Resources Planning and Development, Inc., Summary-Health Systems Plan, 1979 (Box 3, Item 5)
- Health Systems Council, Application for Designation, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Item 6-7)
- Health Resources Planning and Development, Inc., Health Systems Plan, 1979 (Box 3, Item 8)
- Certificate of Need Application (Box 4, Item 1)
- Project Proposal to the Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania and Pennsylvania Department of Health Division of Need Review for Transitional Infant Care at the Children's Home of Pittsburgh, May 31, 1983 (Box 4, Item 2)
- Certificate of Need Application by Step-by-Step, Inc., 1981 (Box 4, Item 3-4)
- Blueprint of Actions: A Statement of Progress and Promise by the Members of the Pennsylvania Health Council, Inc., 1980 (Box 4, Item 5)
- Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania Guide, 1980 (Box 4, Item 6)
- Certificate of Need Application for Leader Nursing and Rehabilitation Center of Bethel Park, Inc., 1984 (Box 4, Item 7)
- Presbyterian-University Health System, Inc. (Box 4, Item 8)
- Citizens Advisory Council, Annual Report, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Item 9)
- Certificate of Need Application, Heritage Nursing Home, 1981 (Box 4, Item 10)
- The Secretary's Regional Conference on Health Care Costs, December 10-11, 1968 (Box 5, Item 1)
- Testimony of Randy Engel on the Proposed State Health Plan of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, April 16, 1979 (Box 5, Item 2)
- The Preliminary State Health Plan of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, December 16, 1978 (Box 5, Item 3)
- Application for Third Year Conditional Designation of Pennsylvania Department of Health as State Health Planning and Development Agency, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Item 4)
- Statewide Health Coordinating Council Goals, 1979 (Box 5, Item 5)
- Preliminary Draft of the State Health Plan for Review by the State Advisory Council for CHP, Volume I (Box 5, Item 6)
- Application for Full Designation of Pennsylvania Department of Health as State Health Planning and Development Agency, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Item 7)
- The Proposed State Health Plan of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, 1979 (Box 5, Item 8)
- The Proposed State Health Plan for the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, Volume I and II, 1981-1986 (Box 5, Item 9-10)
- Executive Summaries of the Health Planning Resource Document for the Development of a State Health Plan (Box 5, Item 11)
- Health Planning Resource Document for the Development of a State Health Plan, Volume No. 1 (Box 5, Item 12)
- Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania, Guideline Series, 1976-1978 (Box 6, Item 1-4)
- Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania, Annual Report, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Item 5-8)
- By-Laws of the Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania, 1980 (Box 6, Item 9)
- Summary and Annual Implementation Plan, Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Item 10)
- Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania, Principles and Procedures for Planning and Review of Health Services Proposals, May 1978 (Box 6, Item 11)
- Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania, Regional Project Review Committee Report, May 1978 (Box 6, Item 12)
- Annual Project Review Report of the Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Item 13)
- Proposed Revisions to the Health Systems Plan for Southwestern Pennsylvania, 1982 (Box 6, Item 14)
- The Health Systems Plan for Southwestern Pennsylvania, March 1978 (Box 6, Item 15-16)
- Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania, Application for Full Designation, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Item 17)
- Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania, Annual Grant Application, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Item 18-19)
- Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania, Procedures and Criteria for Review of Proposed Uses of Federal Funds, December 17, 1979 (Box 6, Item 20)
- Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania, Proposed Procedures for Review of the Appropriateness of Existing Institutional Health Services (Box 6, Item 21)
- Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania, Certificate of Need Procedures, September 17, 1980 (Box 6, Item 22)
- The Pattern of Utilization of Inpatient Hospital Services in Southwestern Pennsylvania, November 1980 (Box 6, Item 23)
- Implications of an Aging Population for the Health Care System in Southwestern Pennsylvania, August 1981 (Box 6, Item 24)
- Northwestern Pennsylvania's Grant Application for Health Systems Agency Designation, 1979 (Box 6, Item 25-27)
- Health Systems Plan for Northwestern Pennsylvania, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Item 28-31)
- Allegheny General Hospital Certificate of Need Application, 1986 (Box 6, Item 32)
- Western Pennsylvania Regional Medical Program, Annual Report and Continuation Application, February 1973 (Box 6, Item 33)
- Report of the State of Maryland Commission to Study Hospital Costs, 1964 (Box 7, Item 1)
- Development of the Community Health Center Plan in New Haven, CT, 1973 (Box 7, Item 2)
- Percutaneous Transluminal Coronary Angioplasty (PTCA) Laboratory, Shadyside Hospital, 1985 (Box 7, Item 3)
- Health Systems Agency Summary Profile (Box 7, Item 4)
- The Distribution and Analysis of Health Resources and Hospital Utilization in Western Pennsylvania, 1966-1975 (Box 7, Item 5)
- Forbes Health System Certificate of Need Application for the Provision of Computerized Tomography Services at the Columbia Health Center, 1982 (Box 7, Item 6)
- Report of the Secretary's Commission on Medical Malpractice, 1973 (Box 7, Item 7-8)
- Background Survey and Analysis for a Hospital Study Design, 1961 (Box 7, Item 9)
- Group Leader's Handbook, March 1, 1951 (Box 7, Item 10)
- Medical Care: Official Journal of the Medical Care Section, American Public Health Association, March 1976 (Box 7, Item 11)
- Group Health and Welfare News, March 1976 (Box 7, Item 12)
- Hospital Week, March 12, 1976 (Box 7, Item 13)
- Research and Statistics Note, 1976 (Box 7, Item 14)
- Chiropractic History: Lost, Strayed or Stolen by Russell W. Gibbons, 1976 (Box 7, Item 15)
- The Nation's Health: The Official Newspaper of the American Public Health Association, March 1976 (Box 7, Item 16)
- The Mercy Hospital of Pittsburgh, Annual Report, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Item 17)
- Supplement to a Handbook for Consumer Participation in Health Care Planning, 1979 (Box 7, Item 18)
- The Nation's Health... A Challenge for the 1970s, 1969 (Box 7, Item 19)
- Public Law 93-641: Highlights of the National Conference for Health Service Leaders, May 5-7, 1975 (Box 7, Item 20)
- The First Two Clinical Operational Years of the Community Health Care Center Plan, Inc., November 5, 1973 (Box 7, Item 21)
- Health Affairs, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Item 22-25)
- Health Policy Institute (Box 7, Item 26)
- Your Medicare Handbook, 1978 (Box 7, Item 27)
- Report to the Children's Home of Pittsburgh, April 1983 (Box 7, Item 28)
- Buying Quality Health Care, 1987 (Box 7, Item 29)
- Physicians and Society: Renegotiating the Contract by John K. Iglehart, 1987 (Box 7, Item 30)
- NY-Penn Health Systems Agency, Application for Renewal of Full Designation, 1978-1980 (Box 7, Item 31-32)
- Central Pennsylvania Health Systems Agency, Inc., "Complete Application for 2nd Year of Full Designation", 1979 (Box 8, Item 1)
- NY-Penn Health Systems Agency, Inc. Progress Report, March 30, 1979 (Box 8, Item 2)
- Health Systems Agency of Southeastern Pennsylvania, Draft Criteria and Standards for the Review of Proposed Capital Expenditures, 1978 (Box 8, Item 3)
- Addendum, Health Systems Agency of Southeastern Pennsylvania Redesignation Hearings, November 28, 1977 (Box 8, Item 4)
- Health Systems Agency Annual Baseline Report, December 1978 (Box 8, Item 5)
- Health Systems Agency Monitoring/Reporting System, 1979 (Box 8, Item 6)
- Health Systems Agency of Southeastern Pennsylvania, Application for Continued Conditional Designation, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Item 7)
- Health Systems Agency of Northeast Pennsylvania, Application for Renewal Designation, February 1979 (Box 8, Item 8)
- Health Systems Agency of Northeast Pennsylvania, Annual Implementation Plan, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Item 9)
- Keystone Health Systems Agency, Application for Continued Designation as a Health Systems Agency, 1979 (Box 8, Item 10)
- Keystone Health Systems Agency, Health Systems Plan, March 1979 (Box 8, Item 11)
- Keystone Health Systems Agency, Annual Implementation Plan, March 1979 (Box 8, Item 12)